imoney.ph 2019-03-29

# iMoney's Privacy Statement. Find Out More Here! | iMoney Philippines

## iMoney Privacy and Personal Data Protection Policy Statement

iMoney is all about empowering consumer choice, giving you all the information you need to make smart financial decisions. To show that we value your privacy, we are empowering you to decide on the personal information you share with us, and let you in on how we use it.

After all, making intelligent decisions is what iMoney is all about.

iMoney provides its consumers with a comparative listing of various financial products to assist the consumer in making smart financial decisions. In particular, iMoney assists its consumers in choosing the optimal credit card, loan, broadband plan, savings account, investment plan, and insurance plan based on the preferences, spending habits, and practices of the consumer, by providing information necessary to the consumer. iMoney may likewise assist the consumer in applying for the enumerated financial products with third parties and duly coordinate with third-party financial institutions, insurance companies, and service providers on behalf of the consumer for this purpose. 

iMoney commits to protect your personal information by complying with the operative legislation concerning personal data protection in the Philippines, namely Republic Act No. 10173, otherwise known as the “Data Privacy Act of 2012” ("DPA").

This Privacy and Personal Data Protection Policy (“Policy”) details how iMoney collects and uses your personal data, and informs you about the personal data protection measures iMoney has put in place.

In providing the Services to you, iMoney may collect, store, and use your personal data. To access our Services, or to process a transaction between yourself and a third party, we may request personal information such as your name, address, phone number, email address and other information that renders you identifiable. Thus, when you opt to avail of iMoney’s Services, you consent to the collection, storage, use, disclosure, transfer, and processing of your information only as described in this Policy.

Unless you provide your personal information for the use of iMoney’s Services, you remain anonymous when you browse this website. We do not collect personal information if you are only browsing this website. 

iMoney collects personal information from you only when you choose to provide the same to iMoney when you use our Services, such as when you apply for a financial product with a third-party financial institution through our website, or when you provide personal information to iMoney through our call center agents. This personal information encompasses information communicated to us when you voluntarily complete an application form presented on our website, which makes it possible to identify you. By volunteering personal information, you undertake to communicate accurate and up-to-date information that does not prejudice the interest of any third parties.

We implement reasonable and appropriate security measures required under the DPA when we collect, store, and process your personal information in the Philippines. We shall comply with the applicable laws and regulations should we transfer the storage and/or processing of your personal information outside the country.

Upon giving us consent, we may collect, store, use, disclose, transfer, and/or process the information for the following purposes: 

  * Refer you to the financial product(s), and/or financial institutions (or their authorized representatives) specified by you while completing application forms on our website; and/or
  * To enable you to access and use iMoney's services; and/or
  * To personalize and improve aspects of our overall service to you and our other users, as well as carrying out research such as analyzing market trends and customer demographics; and/or
  * To communicate with you, in order to verify the personal information provided, or to request any additional information that is vital to fulfilling the service you have applied for; and/or
  * To send you information about products and services which we think may be of interest to you; and/or
  * To pass on information about you as set forth in Section 6 below (Passing on information about you).

Where you decided to use iMoney’s services and coursed your application for a financial product through the iMoney website, iMoney may disclose and transmit your personal data together with your application form to your chosen third party financial institution, insurance company, or service provider for further processing by the latter. Once your application form together with your personal data are so transferred, iMoney’s responsibility shall be limited to verifying the accuracy of your personal information. The approval of your application form shall depend entirely on the third party financial institution, insurance company, or service provider.

iMoney may likewise disclose and transfer your personal data to third parties, including financial institutions, whose products are listed on the iMoney website, and which you may have shown interest in while you were browsing through the iMoney website and having left your personal information on our website or to our call center agents.

At no point will we sell, distribute, or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission, or are required to do so under the law.

Collected personal information is retained for the period necessary to carry out the purposes stated in Section 5 (Purpose of Information) above. To protect the confidentiality of your personal data within the context of Section 5 (Purpose of Information) above, iMoney undertakes to exert all reasonable efforts and to take all practical steps to ensure that collected data is protected against any loss, misuse, unauthorized or accidental modification, access or disclosure, alteration or destruction, during the period of retention of the information. We guarantee that your personal data is permanently deleted once it is no longer required to fulfill its original purpose, or as required by the law. 

iMoney takes all reasonable steps to ensure that your information is accurate, complete, not misleading and kept up-to-date, consistent with the purpose for which the information was collected.

You may write to us if you would like access to your personal information, how your personal data were used, any disclosures of your personal data, and/or the reason for the disclosure of your personal data to the intended recipients. You may likewise contact us to correct personal information that is inaccurate, incomplete, misleading or not up-to-date. Finally, should you wish to withdraw your consent to the collection, storage, and use of your personal information, please let us know and we will address your concern. For contact details, please see Section 13 (Inquiry) below. 

We will exert reasonable efforts to resolve and/or address requests for access and information changes, as well as notices on withdrawal of consent, insofar as iMoney’s database is concerned, within a reasonable time from receipt of said request. iMoney shall have no obligation to correct personal information already transmitted to third parties pursuant to your application for the third parties’ financial products.

You agree to receive communications from us via email, post, telephone or by text of products, services and other offers we think may be of interest to you.

Whenever you provide us with personal information, you have an opportunity to object or withdraw your consent to us and others using and sharing your information for marketing purposes. Unless and until we receive your objection or withdrawal of your consent, you are consenting to such uses.

Any electronic marketing communications we send you will include clear and concise instructions to follow should you wish to unsubscribe at any time.

Should you no longer wish to be contacted by us, you can advise us at any time by contacting us on +6326255727 or by sending an email to [privacy@imoney-group.com](mailto:privacy@imoney-group.com) as well as through the contact details in Section 13 (Inquiry) below.

You can also ask us at any time to stop passing your information to third parties for marketing purposes, which we will do.

In order to ensure the Services we provide you continue to meet your needs, we may ask you for feedback on your experience of using the website. Any feedback you provide will only be used as part of our program of continuous improvement and will not be published on the website. 

If you decide to enter into a contract with a third party provider through this website, the information you have provided to us together with any further information requested by, and supplied by you or us to the third party provider will be held by the provider for the purposes set out in that provider's privacy policy. Therefore, you are strongly advised to read your chosen provider's privacy policy and satisfy yourself as to the purposes for which the provider will use your personal information before entering into the contract. We have no responsibility for the uses to which a provider puts your personal information. 

A cookie is a very small text file placed on your computer. Cookies help us to: 

  * understand browsing habits on this Website;
  * understand the number of visitors to this Website and the pages visited; and
  * remember you when you return to this Website so we can provide you with a better browsing experience.

Most cookies are deleted as soon as you close your browser, these are known as session cookies. Others, known as persistent cookies, are stored on your computer either until you delete them or they expire. By using this Service or visiting our website, you consent to us using cookies.

This website uses the following cookies:

**Google Analytics**  
The Google Analytics cookie allows us to see information on user website activity including, but not limited to page views, referral and average time spent on the website. The information is de-personalised and is displayed as numbers, meaning it will not be tracked back to individuals, which helps to protect your privacy. Using Google Analytics we can see what content is popular on our website, and strive to ensure you have the best user experience possible.

**DoubleClick**  
We use Google Analytics remarketing codes to log when users view specific pages or take specific actions on the website. This allows us to provide targeted advertising in the future.  
You can choose to block or delete cookies through your browser settings. If you decide to block or delete our cookies, you will not be able to benefit from the full range of our Services and this may affect the performance of our website on your system.

For questions or concerns regarding this Policy, the processing of your information, and your rights under the DPA, you may contact our Data Protection Officer through the following details:

  * **Contact Number:** 632- 6255727
  * **Email Address:** [privacy@imoney-group.com](mailto:privacy@imoney-group.com)
  * **Office Address:**  
11th Floor VGP Center,  
Ayala Avenue Makati City  
1226 Philippines
